（パズル王）よしっ！　こっちだ。
Excellent! This way!
間違いない！
I'm certain of it.
We're finally here!
来た　来た　来た！　ハハハッ！
ん？！
（カイト）行き止まりだな。
It's a dead end.
ええい　そんなはずは。　ん？！
It can't be!
フッ…　見ろ！
Behold!
I placed eighth in the Asian preliminaries for the Puzzle World Cup! I'm the Puzzle King!
パズルワールドカップ　アジア予選第８位の
このパズル王に→
解けぬパズルは　ないのだ！
There's no puzzle I can't solve!
うわっ！　あっ　あ～！
バカ！　言わんこっちゃねぇ！
This is why I told you...!
なっ　何だ？　こりゃ！
What the hell is this?
Don't stop me! Such a grand puzzle must have a grand prize too!
邪魔するな！　これだけ大仕掛けの
パズルなら　財も　ばく大なはず！
Forget it! Is it worth more than your life?!
やめろって言ってんだろ！
命と　お宝と　どっちが…？
ゲゲッ！　見てるのか！
いちいち　うるせえ！
Do you see that?
Just shut your trap!
これが　パズル？
This is a puzzle?
マジかよ。
Are you kidding me?
いや　違う。
No, I guess not. Puzzles don't endanger lives.
人の命をもてあそぶなんて
パズルじゃねえ。
kimi no nounai he shinnyuu nemutteiru sukima ni
I infiltrate your brain while you're sleeping.
Baby, open the gate!
fukuzatsu sugi sekyuriti kakusareru to abakitaku naru
The security's too tough, but I want to expose what's hidden.
barabara ni chirabatteiru pasuwado wo hiroi atsume
I gather the pieces of the shattered password.
kakushin ni sematte iku sono shoutai wo misete
I get close to the core. Show me who you really are!
kantan ni kuria dekinai saki nante motto yomenai
I can't clear it easily. I can't even see what lies ahead.
kaidoku fukanou sumairu kikenna pazuru
Your indecipherable smile is a hazardous puzzle.
rokku sareta doa aru nara zutto tataite miru beki kazana hiraku wa
When you see a locked door, you should just hit it until a crack opens.
eien ni hodokenai nazo nanka wa nai
There's no mystery that lasts forever!
makiokosu, it's a supernova
I made it, it's a supernova!
tobikiri shigekitekina hirameki wo agemashou
Let's flash so bright it'd hurt!
Misskey-Misskey La-Tu-Ma
yume no naka it's a supernova
In my dreams, it's a supernova!
watashi wa sou brain diver
Yeah, I'm the brain diver!
kimi ga sagashi motometeru kotae ni nareru made
Until I can find the answer you're looking for...
Brain diver!
The Contract Hidden in the Labyrinth
（男子Ａ）なあ　けさのニュース見た？
Have you seen the morning news?
Yeah, I have. Okudera the Genius was saved from near death!
（男子Ｂ）見た見た。　ジーニアス奥寺が
遭難して助けられたってやつな。
Those ruins are just behind our school.
（女子Ａ）あの遺跡
うちの学校の　すぐ裏でしょ。
I know, I was so surprised!
（女子Ｂ）だよね　ビックリ！
Pinched in the mountains, this is cool!
（男子Ｃ）裏山で遭難とか　ウケる！
（男子Ｄ）でもさ　通りかかった
高校生に助けられたって。
The thing is, they say he was saved by a passing high-schooler!
（女子Ｃ）え～っ？！
ありえなくない？
What? There's no way!
So who's this high-schooler then?
（女子Ｄ）…つか　誰？　その高校生。
（男子Ｅ）何だ　これ？
（女子Ｄ）パズル？
What's this?
A puzzle?
（男子Ｆ）なんか　すげえ！
It's amazing!
I even made him breakfast and went to pick him up!
（ノノハ）
…ったく　もう　せっかく朝ごはん
作って　迎えに行ってやったのに。
カイトのやつ。　先に行くんなら
前の日に言えってえの。
That damn Kaito, he should've told me he was leaving earlier!
What's that?
何　これ？
迷路じゃない。
面白そう！
Looks like a labyrinth.
Looks fun!
はっ？　何　これ？
What the hell...?
（相沢）エヘヘヘッ！
楽勝っすね　武田さん。
This is easy, isn't it, Takeda?
（武田）ふん！　我ら　√学園の
エリート集団であるパズル部にとっては。
We're the most elite group of the Root Academy, the Puzzle Clu-
（机を置く音）
ひいっ！
何の嫌がらせかな？
自称　天才パズラー君。
Are you playing dirty, Mr. Self-Proclaimed Genius Puzzler?
そこを塞がれたら
解答のルートがなくなってしまうが。
You're blocking the only route to the solution there.
そう　この迷路には
答えがねえんだ。
I know. There is no solution.
ウフン　ふざけるな！
That's ridiculous!
そうだ。
解けないパズルは　パズルじゃない。
Yeah! A puzzle without a solution isn't a puzzle!
実物が　そうなってんだよ。
But the real one is just like this.
Real one? What are you talking about?
（武田）実物？！　何のことだ！
（相沢）ごまかすなよ。
Don't screw with us!
何なんだ？！　この携帯。
What's with this gadget?
なんで　パズル王しか
知らねえはずの遺跡の情報が…。
Only the Puzzle King should have the info on the ruins, and yet...
カイト～～！
Kaito!
なっ　何すん…。　あ～！
Wh-What are-
You puzzle-freak! Return these desks now!
このパズルバカ！　さっさと机
元に戻しなさいよ。
Okay! Okay!
分かった。　分かったから。
I couldn't solve this Sage Puzzle because it was too dangerous!
（パズル王）「私が　この賢者のパズルを
公開しなかったのは→
Distress in the
mysterious ruins!!
Okudera the Genius
tells the truth!!
あまりに
危険なものだったからである。→
あの高校生も　私がいなければ
今ごろは…　湖の底！」。
Was it not for I, that high-schooler would be sleeping on...
the bottom of that lake!
（バロン）分かりました。
大門カイトを停学１０分に処します。
I understand. I suspend Daimon Kaito for ten minutes.
（タマキ）１０分って。
（ソウジ）寛大な処分
感謝致します。
Ten minutes?!
Thank you for your lenient judgment.
何か？
Yes?
（タマキ）
私　前から思ってるんですけど→
I've been wanting to ask this for a while.
Aren't the principal and you
学園長も　生徒会長も
大門君に甘くないですか？
a bit too forgiving with Daimon?
It's just your imagination.
ああ　気のせい　気のせい。
あっ　どちらへ？
パズル部。　生徒会の方はよろしくね。
Where are you going?
To the Puzzle Club. I'll leave the council to you.
Come on...
もう。
やめなって　カイト！
あんたが　パズル部に行ったら→
Stop it, Kaito! If you go to the Puzzle Club, you'll just get in a fight!
もめるに決まってるでしょ。
なんで？
Why's that?
忘れたの？　軸川先輩の入部の勧誘
断ったじゃん。
Did you forget that you rejected Jikugawa's invitation?
You said they weren't good enough.
レベルが低いからって。
事実だろ。
But it's true.
（ノック）
部長いるか？
（一同）おっ！
Is the club president in?
（アイリ）あっ　カイト先輩。　軸川部長は
まだ　いらっしゃってませんよ。
Ah, Kaito! President Jikugawa hasn't come back yet.
じゃ　ちょっと待たせてもらうぜ。
どうぞ　どうぞ。
Then I'll wait for him.
Sure, sure!
E-Excuse us.
しっ　失礼しま～す。
大門カイト君。　けさの　ひどいパズルの
口直しに　僕のナンプレ→
Daimon Kaito! Would you like to try my sudoku to forget that awful puzzle from this morning?
やってみないか？
ん？
ナンプレ？
Sudoku?
You can write in numbers 1 to 9.
空いてるマスに
１～９の数字を入れる。
ただし　縦の列　横の列
太線で囲まれたブロックの中に→
But in every row, column, and the blocks surrounded by thicker lines,
同じ数字が　２つ
入ってはいけない。
you can only write in one of each number.
Huh, what a boring sudoku...
ふ～ん　不細工なナンプレだ。
お前らしいな。
As expected of you.
うっ　言っておくが　そのナンプレは
作った武田さんでさえ→
Let me warn you that even its creator, Takeda, took a whole day to solve that!
解くのに　丸一日かかったんだぞ。
はいよ。
Here.
ギョー！
正解。
すごいです！　カイト先輩！
It's correct.
You're incredible, Kaito!
マジで　レベル違うのね。
You're really on a whole different level.
Kaito! Welcome to the Puzzle Club!
カイト君。　ようこそ！　パズル部へ。
やっと入部する気に…。
ちげぇよ。
Do you feel like joining?
Hell no.
I have a question for you.
あんたに
聞きたいことがあんだよ。
きのう　あんたがくれた　これ。
一体　何なんだよ。
This thing you gave me yesterday. What is it?
回想
よ～し　クリアっと。
Okay, cleared this one too.
次は　足し算クロスか。
So the next one is a cross sum.
楽勝じゃね？
This is easy.
おっし　クリア！
Okay, cleared.
へっ！　今度は　ナンバーエリアときたか。
Now it's a number area game?
よし！
おっ　きれいなブロック分割だな。
This is one tough block cutter.
どれも　作ったやつの顔が
見えねえけど…。
I wonder who made these though...
Okay, cleared.
おっし　クリアっと。
This is the 20th in a row...
これで　２０問連続…。　おっ！
An invitation from the Minotaur?
ミノタウロスの招待状？
指示された場所は
裏山の遺跡だった。
The designated location was the ruins in the mountains.
えっ　じゃあ　パズル王を助けた
謎の高校生って…。
Wait, so then you were the high-schooler who saved the Puzzle King?
金に汚え三流パズラーだけど→
He's a stingy third-rate puzzler,
but I wouldn't sleep well if I'd let him die.
見殺しにしたら
寝ざめが悪いからな。
Jikugawa, what do you think?
先輩　あんた何を考えてる？
それには　無料で
パズルが送信されてくるって。
That you're getting free puzzles sent to that thing.
This isn't about the puzzles! That place is just a deadly labyrinth!
パズルなんかじゃねえ！
あれは　ただの人殺しの迷路だ！
You can quit if you want.
やめてもいいんだよ。
何！
What?!
別にパズルは義務じゃない。
No one's forcing you to solve puzzles.
I thought the club members had problems,
うちの部員には
難しいと思ったけど→
君にも解けないパズルが
あったんだね。
but looks like there's a puzzle even you can't solve.
そいつは僕が処分するよ。
ウッ。
I'll get rid of that for you.
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
[TEL]
あっ　着信。
A message?
何だ？　こいつ。
The hell is this?
（ミノタウロス）「私は　ミノタウロス。
大門カイト　私の招待を受けたまえ」。
I am the Minotaur. Daimon Kaito, accept my invitation.
俺の名前を　何で？
How do you know my name?
「遺跡に眠る『賢者のパズル』に挑戦し
『オルペウスの契約』を結ぶのだ。→
You are to challenge the Sage Puzzle hidden in the ruins and fulfill Orpheus's Contract.
ただし　失敗すれば　命はない」。
However, if you fail, you will die.
ちょっと　命はないって　何それ？！
What do you mean he'll die?!
解く気はないんだろ？
ウッ。
You're not interested, are you?
えっ？
俺に解けないパズルなんか　ねえ。
Huh?
There's no puzzle I can't solve.
うふっ　アインシュタイン。
Einstein!
「このパズル王こそ
２１世紀のアインシュタインなのである！→
I, the Puzzle King, am the Einstein of the 21st century!
Genius Okudera, the Puzzle King
Eighth in the Asian preliminaries!
私が発見した
新たな賢者のパズル。→
I have recently found a Sage Puzzle!
かつて　唯一　そのパズルを解いた
人物が　誰あろう→
The only one who has been able to solve it was the genius, Einstein!
かの天才　アインシュタイン。
これは　彼が残したマップである。→
This is the map he left behind.
そこに隠された財を
手に入れるのは→
And the one who will discover its hidden treasure will be I, the Puzzle K-
このパズル王をおいて他に…」。
アインシュタインは「オルペウスの契約」は
結びませんでしたがね。
Except Einstein didn't fulfill Orpheus's Contract.
The intervention of that man could delay the schedule.
この男の介入で
いささか段取りが。
大勢に影響はないでしょう。
This doesn't change the plan at all.
大丈夫でしょうか？　彼は。
Will he be all right?
大門カイト。
Daimon Kaito. He is one of the few who have the possibility of using Phi Brain,
彼もまた　神のパズルへ至る
ファイ・ブレインの可能性を秘めた存在。
which could eventually lead to the Divine Puzzle.
信じるしかないでしょう。
We have no choice but to believe in him.
カイト　やっぱり行くの？
ああ。
So you're really going, Kaito?
Yeah.
けど　人殺しのパズルだって。
But you said this puzzle is deadly.
だから　行くんだ。
何それ　意味分かんない。
That's why I'm going.
Huh? I don't get it!
あっ。
俺は許せねえんだ。
そんなものを作ったクズ野郎が。
I can't just sit around knowing that the trash who made it are still out there.
カイト…。
俺は　解けないパズルを解いてみせる。
Kaito...
I'll solve this puzzle that can't be solved.
クズ野郎には絶対に負けねえ！
I won't lose to trash.
どうして　そこまで…。
約束したんだ。
Why are you so hell-bent?
It was a promise...
（青年Ｘ）カイト　解いてやれ。
自由にしてやれ。
Kaito. Solve them. Make them free.
不幸なパズルたちを。
Those poor, unhappy puzzles.
（少年ルーク）フフフッ　パズルを
解いている時の君は　すてきだよ。
You're amazing when you're solving puzzles, Kaito.
カイト。
約束？
ノノハ　やっぱり　お前は帰れ。
Promise?
Nonoha, you should go home.
はあっ？
何があるか　分からねえ。
Huh?
We don't know what's in there.
冗談！　私は　カイトのお目付け役よ。
No way! I have to keep an eye on you!
放っておくわけには　いかないの。
I can't let you go in alone!
それに　自分の身は
自分で守れるから。
勝手にしろ。
...and I can protect myself.
Do what you want then.
（ミノタウロス）よく来たな　大門カイト。
You've finally arrived, Daimon Kaito.
ミノタウロスか？　何もんだ？　お前。
The Minotaur? Who are you?
貴様の挑戦を見届ける者。
Someone who will watch over your challenge.
見届ける？
賢者のパズルとは結界。
Watch over it?
The Sage Puzzle is a barrier.
財　すなわち財宝を封じた結界。
A barrier with a treasure sealed inside it.
パズルを解いた者は
その財を手にできるが→
Those who solve the puzzle will obtain that treasure.
失敗すれば　災いが降りかかる。
Those who fail will face great misfortune.
俺は　お宝なんざ　興味はねえ！
パズルを解く。　それだけだ！
I don't give a damn about the treasure!
I'm gonna solve the puzzle. That's all.
期待しよう。　フフフ。
We shall see.
どうする？　カイト。
決まってる。
What now, Kaito?
It's obvious.
パズルタイムの始まりだ。
It's puzzle time!
バスタイムまでには戻るわよ。
Let's get back before bath time!
パズル？
A puzzle?
こいつを解けば　ドアが開くんだ。
うん。
If I solve this, the door will open.
はやっ！
解放！
You're fast!
Open.
（ドアの開く音）
おお！　開いた！
It opened!
現在位置は　入り口のここだ。
Now we're here, at the entrance.
And now what? Wasn't there no solution?
どうするつもり？
答えがないんでしょ？
何だか　気になる場所があるんだ。
気になる場所って？
There's this place I want to check out.
What place?
ああ　理由は分からねえんだけど
ここだ。
I don't really know why,
but it's here.
ん？！　行き止まりじゃん。
そうなんだけどな。
Huh? But that's a dead end.
I know, but still...
ふ～ん。　ねぇ　私に任せて。
おい！　どこ行くんだよ？
Leave it to me!
Hey, where are you going?
To the exit, of course!
出口に決まってるでしょ！
はあっ？
Huh?!
ネットで調べたら　迷路は
壁を触りながら進めば→
I looked it up on the net. If you keep your hand on the wall,
必ず出口にたどりつけるんだって。
おいおい。
you can always find the exit!
Hey!
This labyrinth is nothing!
迷路なんて　チョロイ　チョロイ。
止まれ！
スピード　上げるぞ！
Stop!
Let's speed it up!
なっ？！　やめろって…　ノノハ。
I said cut it out, Nonoha!
ほらほら　遅いぞ。
バカ　戻れ！
Look, you're lagging behind!
Stop, you idiot!
ノノハ！
Nonoha!
うっ　えい！
うっ。
あっ　ありがとう！
Th-Thanks...
バカ！　正解じゃねえルートには
ワナが仕掛けられてんだよ！
Idiot! There are traps in every route but the solution!
ごめん。
いいか。　勝手に進むんじゃねえ。
Sorry.
Listen up. Don't run off by yourself.
Okay.
We should follow the wall back to where we were.
壁伝いに　いったん
元の場所まで戻らねえと→
もう　ここが　どこだか
分かんねえし。
I don't even know where we are now.
さっき言ってた
気になる所へ行くの？
Are we going to that place you wanted to check out?
ああ。
それだったら　こっちかも。
Yeah.
Then I think it's this way.
あっ？
大丈夫　地図は覚えてるから。
Huh?
Don't worry, I remembered the map.
I told you not to run off by yourself!
だから　勝手に行くなっての。
ここでしょ？
お前　ホント　記憶力だけは抜群だな。
This should be it.
At least you have a really good memory.
「だけ」は余計よ。
Leave the "at least" out.
The hell? We're stuck here.
何だ？
何かが引っ掛かるんだけど。
ただの行き止まりだよね。
どこかに謎が隠されているはずだ。
It's just an average dead end, isn't it?
There should be a trigger hidden somewhere.
この空白には何かが隠されてる。
There's something hidden in this space.
行ってみるか。　いや　しかし…。
Should we go there? But...
この一角だけ　他と造りが違うね。
何？！
This corner is made differently...
What?
ああ　大したことじゃないから。
ゴメン　ゴメン。
Ah, nothing, never mind me.
Sorry, sorry.
何だ？　何が違うんだ？
What did you say? What's different?
It's just, umm...
あっ　え～と　柱の組み方が
ずっと横の木が手前だったのに→
Until now, at every column, the horizontal beam was in the front.
ここだけ逆だなって。
パズルに関係ないよね。
But here, it's the other way around.
It has nothing to do with the puzzle, right?
いや　そうか？
I didn't even...
あっ！　斧だ！
どっかに　斧を見なかったか？
It's the axe! Did you see an axe somewhere?
Axe? Axe... I feel like I did...
斧？　斧　どっかで見たような。
あっ　そこの柱に確か…。
Ah, on that column over there!
What?
壁が動いてる。
The wall's moving!
すごい！
Amazing!
よし！　やった！
ほんま。
All right, we did it!
Really?
答えの無い迷路は
その一部が移動したとき→
There is no solution, but if you move a piece of the puzzle, the solution route shows up.
正解のルートが現れるように
なっていたんだ。
うん。
Uh-huh...
あの不自然な空白は
迷路が移動するためのスペース。
That weird space was there because a piece was meant to move into it.
That was the riddle hidden in this puzzle!
これが　このパズルに隠された謎だ。
So that was it! We did it, Kaito!
そういう事か！　やったね　カイト！
ああ。　解けないパズルを解いたぜ！
うん。
Yeah, we solved the unsolvable puzzle!
Yeah!
出口だ。
ウフッ！　やった！
It's the exit.
We did it!
なんだ　こりゃ？
What the hell is this?
すごいんだけど。
It's incredible...
こんなものが
学校の裏山の地下に…。
There was a place like this under the mountain behind the school?
（ミノタウロス）それより先は
１人で進め。
あっ！
From here on, you'll be going alone.
ノノハ　お前は戻れ。
えっ　でも　あっ！　カイト！
Nonoha, you go back.
Hey, but... Ah, Kaito!
Fine! I don't care what happens to you!
もう！　どうなっても
知らないからね！
マンダラ。
A mandala?
うわっ！　何だ　これ？
What the hell?
うわ～っ！
カイト！
Kaito!
あっ！　うそっ！
You're kidding me!
何なのよ。
What's going on?!
You have obtained the treasure. Orpheus's Contract has been fulfilled.
（ミノタウロス）貴様は　財を得た。
「オルペウスの契約」が結ばれたのだ。
Orpheus?
オルペウス？
Daimon Kaito.
大門カイト　これにより　貴様は　脳を
限界まで活性化させる力を得た。
With this, you have gained the power to
fully utilize your brain and push it to its limits.
その力をもって　この場所から
脱出したまえ。
Escape from here using that power.
貴様の目の前にある
３本の縄のうち→
You must choose and pull one of the three ropes in front of you.
どれか１本を選んで　引きたまえ。
その水は　すぐに支えの木
全体に行き渡り→
The water is flowing toward the supporting beams.
やがて　重みに耐えきれず
崩壊する。
Soon, they will not be able to support the weight of the water.
助かりたければ　その前に
縄を引いて→
If you want to survive, you must pull the rope that stops the water's flow.
水門を閉めなくてはならない。
However, if you pull the wrong rope, the ruins will instantly collapse.
ただし　間違った２本を引けば
遺跡は　そこで全壊する。
はあっ？！　何　それ？
全壊とかって　意味分かんない！
What?! Collapse my ass!
どれだ？
どれが　どう　つながっている。
Which one is it?
How do they connect?
あれは…。　いや　あれは　ダミーだ。
That one...? No, that's a dummy.
落ち着いて　よく見ろ。
Stay calm and examine them.
クソっ！
複雑すぎて　つかめねえ。
Shit!
It's too complex for me to process!
Open... you damn... door!
この！　開かないよ！
早くしねえと　ノノハが…。
If I don't hurry, Nonoha will be...
クッ！　焦るなっ！
I can't rush this!
ううっ！
カイト！
Kaito!
Dammit!
クッソ～っ！
カイト…。
Kaito?
解けた。
Solved.
tsukue no ue de umareta sekai
This world born on my table.
ichiban saki ni kimi ni misetakatta
I wanted you to see it first.
karappo no heya sotto nukedashite hashiri hajimeteta
I sneaked out of the empty room and started to run.
iki hazamasete oka wo noboru to
As I got to the top of the hill, out of breath,
kimi ga saki ni tsuite matteita ne
you were already there waiting for me.
takusan no hajimete kimi to mitsuketa takaramono datta
It was the first of many treasures we would find together.
kanashisa de afureta toki wa
When sorrow was overflowing in me,
nanimo iwazu ni tada soba ni ite kureta ne
you just silently stayed by my side.
ima de mo wasurenai yo
I still haven't forgotten that.
mata aou ne yakusoku wo shiyou
Let's promise we'll meet again.
kie wa shinai ano hi no sayonara
The goodbye of that day we'll never forget.
boku no subete kimi ga kureta michi
All I have I got from you,
zutto kokoro no naka hikaru yo
and it will all shine in my heart forever.
Preview